# Minh Nguyen

### Audio Programmer

<u>nali.minh.ng@gmail.com</u>

| 📞 (213) 458-4705

https://nalimusic.github.io/ | Seattle, WA 98122

Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience in computer science research. Proven skills in Programming, Audio Production, Sound Design, Game Engine, Middleware, and Data Mining. Author of 1 patent, 7 publications with system work featured on medias. An independent developer and a dedicated team player with interdisciplinary collaboration experiences.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Game Engine & Middleware: Unity, Wwise
- **Digital Audio Workstation:** Pro Tools, Ableton Live
- Platform: Mobile (Android, iOS), PC (Windows, MacOS), Web
- Programming: C++, C#, Python, Java, MATLAB, Max/MSP, JavaScript, Ruby, Database SQL, NoSQL
- Digital Signal Processing/Al tool: NumPy, Matplotlib, NLTK, Weka, TensorFlow, PyTorch
- Others: Agile methodology, Git, Sound Design, Recording & Mixing, Interdisciplinary & Collaborative research

#### **EDUCATION**

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA, LOS ANGELES HO CHI MINH CITY UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY, VIETNAM UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON, SEATTLE **SCHOOL OF VIDEO GAME AUDIO** 

MSc. in Computer Science: Signal Processing, Machine Learning Honors BEng. in Computer Science & Engineering Certificate in Audio Production: Music & Video Post-Production Game Audio: Wwise, FMOD, Unity, Unreal Engine

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES**

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER, Seattle, WA**

09/2020 - Present

 Developing PC, Android & iOS mobile application to play spatial (ambisonics, binaural) music using Google Resonance Audio SDK, Oculus Audio Spatializer, Unity, C#, Java.

#### **QA TESTER,** MAAT Digital - Remote

04/2021 - Present

- Manual beta & release testing for 15 audio mastering plugins on multiple DAWs (Ableton Live, Seguoia, Nuendo).
- Software version tracking & documenting / reporting on bugs. Collaborating with 2 software developers.

#### TECHNICAL INTERN, Women's Audio Mission (WAM) - San Francisco, CA

01/2021 - 05/2021

- Teaching Assistant for 2 Music Coding classes using Python as part of Girls on The Mic program.
- Video & audio production: dialogue, music, visuals for WAM's social content and events using Pro Tools, RX, After Effects.
- Technical supporting for WAM online streaming events (Girls on The Mic Showcase, WAMcon Virtual Nashville).

#### **RESEARCH FELLOW,** IBM Research AI - Yorktown Heights, NY

05/2017 - 09/2017

- Developing Simpler Voice: Overcoming Illiteracy an AI natural language processing system for low-literate adults by decoding complex texts into simple messages, visual & audio elements.
- Working with 5 Research Scientists & Software Engineers at IBM Research AI and NGO Literacy Coalition of Central Texas.
- Publishing 1 patent & presenting at NeurIPS 2017, D4GX 2018 conferences. Media featuring on Mashable, ACM, IBM.

#### RESEARCH ASSISTANT, USC Integrated Media Systems Center - Los Angeles, CA

2014 - 2017

- Developing ATOM-HP a system supporting physicians to quantify performance of cancer patients during chemotherapy by analyzing signals from wearables worn by patients & 3D camera sensors. Deploying the system, writing system manual & technical supporting on-site/on-phone at 3 local LA hospitals with 55 patients participated.
- Interdisciplinary research. Collaborating with a team of 20+ Oncologists, Physicians, Biomedical scientists.
- Publishing 4 papers. Presenting at AMIA 2016, ICDM 2017 conferences. Featuring on Forbes, NBC4News, The Hill, ScienceDaily.

#### **RESEARCH STUDENT,** Ho Chi Minh city University of Technology, Vietnam

2012 - 2014

- Developing a mobile phone authentication framework (Android & iOS) using human voice & facial recognition.
- Publishing 1 paper.

## WEB DEVELOPER INTERN, East Agile Vietnam

05/2012 - 09/2012

- Developing, testing & deploying an internal Human Resources web application using Ruby, Ruby-on-Rails framework.
- Pair programming. Agile methodology (TDD, BDD).

#### **HONORS & AWARDS**

- 2021. Game Audio Diversity Alliance scholarship
- 2020. SoundGirls' Leslie Ann Jones scholarship in Honor of Ethel Gabriel
- 2014-2017. Vietnam Education Foundation fellowship. Top 40 national students in STEM
- 2017. IBM Social Good fellowship
- 2016. USC Grace Hopper scholarship
- 2009-2014. Honor scholarships

# OTHER PROFESSIONAL & COMMUNITY SERVICES

- o Volunteer: The Vera Project (2020), Grace Hopper Conference (2016), International Conference on Data Mining (2015)
- o Mentor: Mentoring high school & undergrad students on summer projects at USC (2014 - 2017)
- Guest Lecturer & Teaching Assistant: CS-585 Database Systems (2016, 2017), INF-552 Machine Learning for Data Informatics (2015)
- Member: AES, IEEE, SoundGirls, Grammy U